A Guide to the Stanford Moore papers, Rockefeller University Faculty FA111
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Professional Travel and Activities, 1945-1982; 6
  - Travel
    - Taiwan, 1976 (Box 111, Folder 922, Folder 921, Folder 923)
    - Texas and Tennessee, 1976 (Box 111, Folder 924)
    - USSR, 1976 (Box 111, Folder 925)
    - Europe, 1977 (Box 112, Folder 926)
    - France, 1977 (Box 112, Folder 927)
    - Tennessee, 1977 (Box 112, Folder 928)
    - Europe, 1978 (Box 112, Folder 929)
    - Minnesota, 1978 (Box 112, Folder 930)
    - Padua, 1978 (Box 112, Folder 931)
    - Spain, 1978 (Box 113, Folder 932)
    - Tennesse, 1978 (Box 113, Folder 933)
    - Wisconsin, 1978 (Box 113, Folder 934)
    - California, 1979 (Box 113, Folder 935)
    - Iowa, 1979 (Box 113, Folder 936)
    - Oneonta, 1979 (Box 113, Folder 937)
    - Toronto, 1979 (Box 113, Folder 938)
    - Australia, 1982 (Box 113, Folder 939)
  - Conferences - General
    - "Concerning Conferences" by Alexander King (Box 113, Folder 940)
    - "How Conferences?" by D.K.C. MacDonald (Box 113, Folder 941)
    - Invitations (Box 113, Folder 942)
    - Scheduled Meetings and Conferences (Box 113, Folder 943)
    - New York Academy of Sciences, Conference on Chromatography, 1946 (Box 113, Folder 944)
    - Cornell Seminars, 1947 (Box 113, Folder 945)
    - IUPAC [International Union of Pure and Applied Chemistry] and Insulin, 1955-1956 (Box 114, Folder 946)
    - Gordon Conferences, 1957-1966 (Box 114, Folder 947)
    - National Committee for Biochemistry, Minutes, 1962-1967 (Box 114, Folder 948)
    - National Academy of Sciences Centennial, 1963 (Box 114, Folder 949)
    - Nineteenth International Congress of Pure and Applied Chemistry, London, 1964 (Box 114, Folder 950)
    - European Convention of Chemical Engineering, Frankfurt, 1964 (Box 114, Folder 951)
    - Federation of European Biochemical Societies, First Meeting, London, 1964 (Box 114, Folder 952)
    - National Committee for Biochemistry, 1964 (Box 114, Folder 953)
    - One Hundred and First Annual Meeting, National Academy of Sciences, Washington, D.C., 1964 (Box 114, Folder 954)
    - Pan-American Association of Biochemical Societies, 1969 (Box 114, Folder 955)
    - First International Congress of Immunology, Washington, D.C., 1971 (Box 114, Folder 956)
    - Third American Peptide Symposium, 1972 (Box 114, Folder 957)
    - Congress in Stockholm, 1973 (Box 114, Folder 958)
    - Conference on Host Resistance, 1976 (Box 114, Folder 959)
    - Select Committee on GRAS [Generally Recognized as Safe] Substances, 1977 (Box 115, Folder 960)
    - National Institutes of Health Symposium, 1980 (Box 115, Folder 961)
  - American Society of Biological Chemists
    - "The First Twenty-five Years of the American Society of Biological Chemists" by Russell H. Chittenden, 1945 (Box 115, Folder 962)
    - Breakfasts and Luncheons, 1966-1978 (Box 115, Folder 963)
    - Committee on Federation, 1968-1969 (Box 115, Folder 964)
    - 1969 (Box 115, Folder 965)
    - Denver, 1969 (Box 115, Folder 966)
    - San Francisco, 1969-1970 (Box 115, Folder 967)
    - Parliamentary Procedures, 1969-1971 (Box 115, Folder 968)
    - Journal of Biological Chemistry, 1969-1976 (Box 116, Folder 969)
    - Nominations, 1969-1982 (Box 116, Folder 970)
    - 1970 (Box 116, Folder 971)
    - Council, 1970-1971 (Box 116, Folder 972, Box 117, Folder 973)
    - Harte, 1970-1971 (Box 117, Folder 974)
    - San Francisco, 1972 (Box 117, Folder 975)
    - Atlantic City, 1972 (Box 117, Folder 976)
    - Movie Committee, 1972 (Box 117, Folder 977)
    - Denver, 1974 (Box 117, Folder 978)
    - Minneapolis, 1974 (Box 117, Folder 979)
    - By-Laws, 1977-1979 (Box 117, Folder 980)
  - Federation of American Societies for Experimental Biology
    - Federation of American Societies for Experimental Biology (Box 118, Folder 981)
    - Edward E. David, Jr. (Box 118, Folder 982)
    - Eugene Hess (Box 118, Folder 983)
    - Robert Krauss (Box 118, Folder 984)
    - Moore - President (Box 118, Folder 985)
    - Search Committee (Box 118, Folder 986)
  - International Congress of Biochemistry
    - Third International Congress of Biochemistry, Brussels, 1955 (Box 118, Folder 987)
    - Fourth International Congress of Biochemistry, Vienna, 1958 (Box 118, Folder 988)
    - Fifth International Congress of Biochemistry, Moscow, 1961 (Box 118, Folder 989)
    - Sixth International Congress of Biochemistry, 1964 (Box 118, Folder 990)
    - Sixth International Congress of Biochemistry, Abstracts (Box 118, Folder 991)
    - Sixth International Congress of Biochemistry, Action File (Box 118, Folder 992)
    - Sixth International Congress of Biochemistry, Addresses (Box 119, Folder 993)
    - Sixth International Congress of Biochemistry, Americana (Box 119, Folder 994)
    - Sixth International Congress of Biochemistry, Circular (Box 119, Folder 995)
    - Sixth International Congress of Biochemistry, Dinners (Box 119, Folder 996)
    - Sixth International Congress of Biochemistry, John T. Edsall (Box 119, Folder 997)
    - Sixth International Congress of Biochemistry, Executive Committee (Box 119, Folder 998)
    - Sixth International Congress of Biochemistry, Exhibit Manager (Box 119, Folder 999)
    - Sixth International Congress of Biochemistry, Finance Committee (Box 119, Folder 1000)
    - Sixth International Congress of Biochemistry, Hilton (Box 119, Folder 1001)
    - Sixth International Congress of Biochemistry, Laboratory Visits (Box 120, Folder 1002)
    - Sixth International Congress of Biochemistry, Ladies Program (Box 120, Folder 1003)
    - Sixth International Congress of Biochemistry, Letters of Acknowledgment (Box 120, Folder 1004)
    - Sixth International Congress of Biochemistry, Local Arrangements Committee (Box 120, Folder 1005)
    - Sixth International Congress of Biochemistry, National Science Foundation Grant (Box 120, Folder 1006)
    - Sixth International Congress of Biochemistry, New York City, 1964 (Box 120, Folder 1007)
    - Sixth International Congress of Biochemistry, New York Convention Bureau (Box 121, Folder 1008)
    - Sixth International Congress of Biochemistry, New York Convention Services (Box 121, Folder 1009)
    - Sixth International Congress of Biochemistry, Organizing Committee (Box 121, Folder 1010)
    - Sixth International Congress of Biochemistry, Press Committee (Box 121, Folder 1011)
    - Sixth International Congress of Biochemistry, Program Committee (Box 122, Folder 1012)
    - Sixth International Congress of Biochemistry, Public Health Service Grant (Box 122, Folder 1013)
    - Sixth International Congress of Biochemistry, Publications Committee (Box 122, Folder 1014)
    - Sixth International Congress of Biochemistry, Secretariat Robert A. Harte (Box 122, Folder 1015)
    - Sixth International Congress of Biochemistry, Travel Committee (Box 122, Folder 1016)
    - Sixth International Congress of Biochemistry, Visas (Box 122, Folder 1017)
    - Seventh International Congress of Biochemistry, Tokyo, 1967 (Box 122, Folder 1018)
    - Tenth International Congress of Biochemistry, Hamburg, 1976 (Box 122, Folder 1019)
    - Eleventh International Congress of Biochemistry, Toronto, 1979 (Box 122, Folder 1020)
  - Rockefeller University
    - Ad Hoc Committee on Honorary Degrees (Box 123, Folder 1021)
    - Board of Scientific Directors (Box 123, Folder 1022)
    - Chemist Search (Box 123, Folder 1023)
    - Chemist Search, Thomas Kaiser (Box 123, Folder 1024)
    - Hospital Search Committee, Jan L. Breslow (Box 123, Folder 1025)
    - Hospital Search Committee, Charles Cantor (Box 123, Folder 1026)
    - Hospital Search Committee, Hans-Joachim Fritz (Box 123, Folder 1027)
    - Hospital Search Committee, July 1981 (Box 123, Folder 1028)
    - Hospital Search Committee, Attallah Kappas (Box 123, Folder 1029)
    - Hospital Search Committee, Adel Mahmoud (Box 123, Folder 1030)
    - Hospital Search Committee, Moore Letter of Resignation, 1982 (Box 123, Folder 1031)
    - Hospital Search Committee, Notes (Box 123, Folder 1032)
    - Hospital Search Committee, Roger N. Rosenberg (Box 123, Folder 1033)
    - Hospital Search Committee, Larry J. Shapiro (Box 123, Folder 1034)
    - Annual Reports, 1969-1974 (Box 124, Folder 1035)
    - Annual Reports, 1975-1981 (Box 124, Folder 1036)
    - Calendar of Events (Box 124, Folder 1037)
    - Convocation, June 8, 1977 (Box 124, Folder 1038)
    - Council (Box 124, Folder 1039)
    - Development of Neurosciences Report, 1976 (Box 124, Folder 1040)
    - Development Office (Box 124, Folder 1041)
    - Fund Raising (Box 125, Folder 1043, Box 124, Folder 1042, Folder 1045, Folder 1044)
    - Memoranda (Box 125, Folder 1046)
    - Press (Box 125, Folder 1047)
    - Research Profiles (Box 125, Folder 1048)
    - Frederick Seitz (Box 125, Folder 1049)
    - Seventy-fifth Reunion, 1976 (Box 125, Folder 1050)
    - William H. Stein Memorial (Box 125, Folder 1051)
  - Vanderbilt University
    - Vanderbilt Board of Trustees (Box 126, Folder 1053, Folder 1052)
    - Vanderbilt Visiting Professorship (Box 126, Folder 1056, Folder 1054, Folder 1055)
- Nobel Prize, 7
  Series 7, Nobel Prize, is arranged alphabetically.
  Series 7, Nobel Prize, holds materials relating to Moore's 1972 Nobel Prize in Chemistry, including congratulatory correspondence, materials on the ceremony and the Nobel Prize Festival, and a folder of clippings.
  - Acknowledgements, Drafts (Box 127, Folder 1057)
  - Acknowledgements, A-C (Box 127, Folder 1058)
  - Acknowledgements, D-J (Box 127, Folder 1059)
  - Acknowledgements, K-R (Box 127, Folder 1060)
  - Acknowledgements, S-Z (Box 127, Folder 1061)
  - Clippings (Box 128, Folder 1062)
  - Correspondence (Box 128, Folder 1063)
  - Correspondence and Programs (Box 128, Folder 1064)
  - Nobel Festival (Box 128, Folder 1065, Folder 1066)
  - Nobel Lecture (Box 129, Folder 1067)
  - Nobel Prize, General (Box 129, Folder 1069, Folder 1068)
  - Rockefeller University Press Booklet (Box 129, Folder 1070)
- Manuscripts, 8
  Series 8, Manuscripts, is arranged alphabetically.
  Series 8, Manuscripts, includes manuscripts submitted or given to Moore by associates or members of the Moore-Stein Laboratory, as well as one folder of Moore manuscripts.
  - Bartholeyns (Box 129, Folder 1071)
  - Blackburn and Moore (Box 129, Folder 1072)
  - Boyer, The Enzymes (Box 129, Folder 1073, Box 130, Folder 1074)
  - Dickerson and Geis (Box 130, Folder 1075)
  - Editorial Reviews of Manuscripts (Box 130, Folder 1076)
  - Ettre (Box 130, Folder 1077)
  - Flodin (Box 130, Folder 1078)
  - Funkhouser and Maccoby (Box 130, Folder 1079)
  - Gehrke (Box 130, Folder 1080)
  - Arabinda Guha (Box 130, Folder 1081)
  - Illustrations (Box 131, Folder 1083, Folder 1084, Folder 1082)
  - Instructions to Authors (Box 131, Folder 1085)
  - Kirschenbaum (Box 131, Folder 1086)
  - Model Manuscripts (Box 131, Folder 1087)
  - Moore (Box 131, Folder 1088)
  - Stanford Moore Manuscripts (Box 131, Folder 1089)
  - Walsh (Box 131, Folder 1090)
  - Wollin (Box 131, Folder 1091)
- Reprints, 1940-1982; 9
  Series 9, Reprints, is arranged chronologically and alphabetically.
  Series 9, Reprints, contains two runs of reprints maintained by Moore: Collected Reprints and Moore Reprints. These two sets of reprints are arranged chronologically; any reprints that were not originally files within these two series are arranged alphabetically by title.
  - Collected Reprints
    - 1940-1949 (Box 132, Folder 1092)
    - 1950-1953 (Box 132, Folder 1093)
    - 1954-1957 (Box 132, Folder 1094)
    - 1958-1960 (Box 132, Folder 1095)
    - 1961-1964 (Box 132, Folder 1096)
    - 1965-1967 (Box 133, Folder 1097)
    - 1968-1972 (Box 133, Folder 1098)
    - 1973-1976 (Box 133, Folder 1099)
    - 1977-1979 (Box 133, Folder 1100)
    - 1980-1982 (Box 133, Folder 1101)
  - Moore Reprints
    - 1940-1949 (Box 133, Folder 1102)
    - 1950-1953 (Box 134, Folder 1103)
    - 1954-1957 (Box 134, Folder 1104)
    - 1958-1960 (Box 134, Folder 1105)
    - 1961-1964 (Box 134, Folder 1106)
    - 1964-1966 (Box 134, Folder 1107)
    - 1967-1969 (Box 135, Folder 1108)
    - 1970-1972 (Box 135, Folder 1109)
    - 1973-1976 (Box 135, Folder 1110)
    - 1977-1979 (Box 135, Folder 1111)
    - 1980-1982 (Box 135, Folder 1112)
  - Abstract, "Structural Studies on the Proteinase from Group A Streptococci" by Moore, Liu, and Stein (Box 135, Folder 1113)
  - "Activity of the Reduced Zymogen of Streptococcal Proteinase" by Bustin, Lin, Stein, and Moore (Box 135, Folder 1114)
  - "Alkylation and Identification of the Histidine Residues at the Active Site of Ribonuclease" by Crestfield, Stein, and Moore (Box 135, Folder 1115)
  - "Alkylation of the Methionine Residues of Ribonuclease in 8 Μ Urea" by Stark and Stein (Box 135, Folder 1116)
  - Assorted Reprints and Notes (Box 135, Folder 1117)
  - "Automatic Recording Apparatus for Use in the Chromatography of Amino Acids" by Spackman, Stein, and Moore (Box 136, Folder 1118)
  - "Automatic Recording Apparatus for Use in the Chromatography of Amino Acids" by Spackman, Stein, and Moore (Box 136, Folder 1119)
  - "Bovine Pancreatic Deoxyribonuclease A: Isolation, Composition, and Amino Acid Sequences of the Tryptic and Chymotryptic Peptides" by Salnikow, Liao, Moore, and Stein (Box 136, Folder 1120)
  - "Bovine Pancreatic Deoxyribonuclease A: Isolation of Cyanogen Bromide Peptides; Complete Covalent Structure of the Polypeptide Chain" by Liao, Salnikow, Moore, and Stein (Box 136, Folder 1121)
  - "Bovine Pancreatic Deoxyribonucleases A and C: A Proline for Histidine Substitution in Deoxyribonuclease C" by Salnikow and Murphy (Box 136, Folder 1122)
  - "Carbohydrate Characterization, I and II" by Moore and Link (Box 136, Folder 1123)
  - "Carbohydrate Characterization, III" by Lohmar, Dimler, Moore, and Link (Box 136, Folder 1124)
  - "Carbohydrate Characterization, V" by Huebner, Lohmar, Dimler, Moore, and Link (Box 136, Folder 1125)
  - "The Carboxyl-terminal Sequence of Porcine Pepsin" by Dopheide, Moore, and Stein (Box 136, Folder 1126)
  - "Carboxypeptidase from Yeast: Large Scale Preparation and the Application to COOH-terminal Analysis of Peptides and Proteins" by Hayashi, Moore, and Stein (Box 136, Folder 1127)
  - The Characterization of Lactic Acid as the Benzimidazole Derivative" by Dimler and Link (Box 136, Folder 1128)
  - "Chemical Modifications of Ribonuclease" by Stein (Box 136, Folder 1129)
  - "Chemical Properties of Streptococcal Proteinase and Its Zymogen" by Liu, Elliott, Moore, and Stein (Box 136, Folder 1130)
  - "Chemical Structures of Pancreatic Ribonuclease and Deoxyribonuclease" by Moore and Stein (Box 136, Folder 1131)
  - "Chemical Studies on Purified Pepsin" by Stein (Box 136, Folder 1132)
  - "Chromatographic Determinations of the Amino Acid Composition of Proteins" by Stein and Moore (Box 136, Folder 1133)
  - "Chromatography of Adrenotropic Hormone on Ion-exchange Columns" by Dixon, Moore, Stack-Dunne, and Young (Box 136, Folder 1134)
  - "Chromatography of Amino Acids on Starch Columns. Solvent Mixtures for the Fractionation of Protein Hydrolysates" by Moore and Stein (Box 136, Folder 1135)
  - "Chromatography of Amino Acids on Sulfonated Polystyrene Resins" by Moore, Spackman, and Stein (Box 136, Folder 1136)
  - "Chromatography of Amino Acids on Sulfonated Polystyrene Resins" by Moore, Spackman, and Stein (Box 136, Folder 1137)
  - "The Concentrations of Cysteine and Cystine in Human Blood Plasma" by Brigham, Stein, and Moore (Box 136, Folder 1138)
  - "Demonstration of the Presence of a Histidine Residue at the Active Site of Streptococcal Proteinase" by Liu (Box 136, Folder 1139)
  - "Determination of the Tryptophan Content of Proteins by Ion Exchange Chromatography of Alkaline Hydrolysates" by Hugli and Moore (Box 136, Folder 1140)
  - "Enhancement of the Activity of Horse Liver Alcohol Dehydrogenase by Modification of Amino Groups at the Active Sites" by Plapp (Box 136, Folder 1141)
  - "Gas Chromatographic Determination of the Carbamylation of Hemoglobin S by Cyanate" by Manning, Lee, Cerami, and Gillette (Box 136, Folder 1142)
  - "The Homologous and Hybrid Dimers of Ribonuclease A and Its Carboxymethylhistidine Derivatives" by Crestfield and Fruchter (Box 136, Folder 1143)
  - "The Identification of a Glutamic Acid Residue as Part of the Active Site of Ribonuclease T1" by Takahashi, Stein, and Moore (Box 136, Folder 1144)
  - "Identification of L-Methionine S-Sulfoximine as the Diastereoisomer of L-Methionine SR-Sulfoximine That Inhibits Glutamine Synthetase" by Manning, Moore, Rowe, and Meister (Box 136, Folder 1145)
  - "An Improved System for the Chromatography of Amino Acids on Sulfonated Polystyrene Resins" by Moore, Spackman, and Stein (Box 136, Folder 1146)
  - "Inactivation of Chymotrypsin by Cyanate" by Shaw, Stein, and Moore (Box 136, Folder 1147)
  - "The Inactivation of Pepsin by Diazoacetylnorleucine Methyl Ester" by Rajagopalan, Stein, and Moore (Box 136, Folder 1148)
  - "Increased Survival of Sickle-Cell Erythrocytes after Treatment In Vitro with Sodium Cyanate" by Gillette, Manning, and Cerami (Box 136, Folder 1149)
  - "Involvement of a Tyrosine Residue in the Activity of Bovine Pancreatic Deoxyribonuclease A" by Hugli and Stein (Box 136, Folder 1150)
  - "L-Cystathionine in Human Brain" by Tallan, Moore, and Stein (Box 136, Folder 1151)
  - "Modification of the Methionine Residues in Ribonuclease" by Neumann, Moore, and Stein (Box 136, Folder 1152)
  - "Muramic Acid Phosphate as a Component of the Mucopeptide of Gram-positive Bacteria" by Liu and Gotschlich (Box 136, Folder 1153)
  - "The Nature of the Amino Acid Residues Involved in the Inactivation of Ribonuclease by Iodoacetate" by Gundlach, Stein, and Moore (Box 136, Folder 1154)
  - "Observations of the Amino Acid Composition of Human Heloglobins" by Stein (Box 136, Folder 1155)
  - "On the Aggregation of Bovine Pancreatic Ribonuclease" by Crestfield, Stein, and Moore (Box 136, Folder 1156)
  - "On the Alkylation of Amino Acid Residues at the Active Site of Ribonuclease" by Heinrickson (Box 136, Folder 1157)
  - "On the Cleavage of Disulfide Bonds in Proteins by Reduction" by Moore, Cole, Gundlach, and Stein (Box 136, Folder 1158)
  - "On the Cysteine Content of Human Hemoglobin" by Cole, Stein, and Moore (Box 136, Folder 1159)
  - "On the Determination of Cystine as Cystic Acid" by Moore (Box 136, Folder 1160)
  - "On the Preparation of Bovine Pancreatic Ribonuclease A" by Crestfield, Stein, and Moore (Box 136, Folder 1161)
  - "On the Reversible Reaction of Cyanate with Sulfhydryl Groups and the Determination of NH2-terminal Cysteine and Cystine in Proteins" by Stark (Box 136, Folder 1162)
  - "On the Sequence of Residues 11 to 18 in Bovine Pancreatic Ribonuclease" by Smyth, Stein, and Moore (Box 136, Folder 1163)
  - "On the Specificity of Streptococcal Proteinase" by Gerwin, Stein, and Moore (Box 136, Folder 1164)
  - "On the Structure of Ribonuclease Dimer" by Fruchter and Crestfield (Box 136, Folder 1165)
  - "Partition Chromatography of Amino Acids on Starch" by Moore and Stein (Box 136, Folder 1166)
  - "Pepsin from Pepsinogen: Preparation and Properties" by Rajagopalan, Moore, and Stein (Box 136, Folder 1167)
  - "Photometric Ninhydrin Method for Use in the Chromatography of Amino Acids" by Moore and Stein (Box 136, Folder 1168)
  - "Potassium Cyanate as an Inhibitor of the Sickling in vitro of Red Blood Cells" by Cerami and Manning (Box 136, Folder 1169)
  - "The Precision and Sensitivity of Amino Acid Analysis" by Moore (Box 136, Folder 1170)
  - "The Preparation of 2-(Aldo-Polyhydroxyalkyl)-Benzimidazoles" by Moore and Link (Box 136, Folder 1171)
  - "The Preparation and Characterization of an Active-Derivative of Bovine Pancreatic Deoxyribonuclease A Formed by Selective Cleavage with α-Chymotrypsin" by Hugli (Box 136, Folder 1172)
  - "Preparation and Chemical Properties of Purified Stem and Fruit Bromelains" by Ota, Moore, and Stein (Box 136, Folder 1173)
  - "The Preparation and Enzymatic Hydrolysis of Reduced and S-Carboxymethylated Proteins" by Crestfield, Moore, and Stein (Box 136, Folder 1174)
  - "Preparation of Pancreatic Ribonucleases 1-114 and 1-115 and Their Reactivation by Mixture with Synthetic COOH-terminal Peptides" by Hayashi, Moore, and Merrifield (Box 136, Folder 1175)
  - "Preparation and Properties of Two Active Forms of Ribonuclease Dimer" by Fruchter and Crestfield (Box 136, Folder 1176)
  - "Properties of Chromatographically Purified Trypsin Inhibitors from Lima Beans" by Jones, Moore, and Stein (Box 136, Folder 1177)
  - "Properties and Conformation of the Histidine Residues at the Active Site of Ribonuclease" by Crestfield, Stein, and Moore (Box 136, Folder 1178)
  - "Properties of the Single Sulfhydryl Group of Streptococcal Proteinase" by Gerwin (Box 136, Folder 1179)
  - "The Reaction of Iodoacetate with Methionine" by Gundlach, Moore, and Stein (Box 136, Folder 1180)
  - "Reactions of the Cyanate Present in Aqueous Urea with Amino Acids and Proteins" by Stark, Stein, and Moore (Box 136, Folder 1181)
  - "Reactivation of des(119-124) Ribonuclease A by Mixture with Synthetic COOH-terminal Peptides; the Role of Phenylalanine-120" by Lin, Gutte, Moore, and Merrifield (Box 137, Folder 1182)
  - "Reactivation of des(119-, 120-, or 121-124) Ribonuclease A by Mixture with Synthetic COOH-terminal Peptides of Varying Lengths" by Gutte, Lin, Caldi, and Merrifield (Box 137, Folder 1183)
  - "The Reactivities of the Histidine Residues at the Active Site of Ribonuclease toward Halo Acids of Different Structures" by Heinrikson, Stein, Crestfield, and Moore (Box 137, Folder 1184)
  - "Recherches mettant en oeuvre les méthodes de Chromotographie sure Collones d'Échangeurs d'Ions, 1950-1957" (Box 137, Folder 1185)
  - "Relationships between the Conformation of Ribonuclease and Its Reactivity toward Iodoacetate" by Stark, Stein, and Moore (Box 137, Folder 1186)
  - "Relationships between Structure and Activity of Ribonuclease" by Stein and Moore (Box 137, Folder 1187)
  - "Reversibility of Denaturation of the Zymogen and the Proteolyzed Zymogen of Streptococcal Proteinase" by Lin and Bustin (Box 137, Folder 1188)
  - "A Sample Injector for Ion Exchange Chromatography and a Flow Cell for Continuous Photometry at 210 mμ" by Crestfield (Box 137, Folder 1189)
  - "Sample Injector for Ion Exchange Chromatography and Flow Cell for Continuous Photometry at 210 Millimicrons" by Crestfield (Box 137, Folder 1190)
  - "The Sequence of Amino Acid Residues in Bovine Pancreatic Ribonuclease: Revisions and Confirmations" by Smyth, Stein, and Moore (Box 137, Folder 1191)
  - "The Sequence of Amino Acid Residues and the Sulfydryl Group at the Active Site of Streptococcal Proteinase" by Liu, Stein, Moore, and Elliott (Box 137, Folder 1192)
  - "The Specific Alkylation by Iodoacetamide of Histidine-12 in the Active Site of Ribonuclease" by Fruchter and Crestfield (Box 137, Folder 1193)
  - "Streptococcal Proteinase" by Moore (Box 137, Folder 1194)
  - "Streptococcal Proteinase: the Zymogen to Enzyme Transformation" by Liu and Elliott (Box 137, Folder 1195)
  - "Structural and Immunological Studies on the Pneumococcal C Polysaccharide" by Gotschlich and Liu (Box 137, Folder 1196)
  - "La Structure et l'Activité de le Ribonuclease Pancréatique" by Moore (Box 137, Folder 1197)
  - "Structure-Activity Relationships in Ribonuclease" by Stein (Box 137, Folder 1198)
  - "The Structure and the Activity of Ribonuclease" by Stein (Box 137, Folder 1199)
  - "The Structure of Proteins" by Stein and Moore (Box 137, Folder 1200)
  - "Studies on the Solubilization of 2', 3'-cyclic Nucleotide 3'-phosphohydrolase from Bovine Brain" by Lundblad and Moore (Box 137, Folder 1201)
  - "Studies on the Tryptophan Residues in Porcine Pepsin" by Dopheide and Jones (Box 137, Folder 1202)